/* Created Code by Prashanthi*/

var quiz = {
    "JS": [
    {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "who was the first president of the united states?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "George Washington",
    "b": "Thomas Gefferson",
    "c": "Abraham Lincoln",
    "d": "Franklin D.Rooselevelt"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "George Washington",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Which ancient civilization built the great Pyramid of Giza?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Egyptians",
    "b": "Greeks",
    "c": "Romanas",
    "d": "Mesopotamians"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Egyptians",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Who was the first ancient roam?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Romulus",
    "b": "Rumus",
    "c": "Julius Caesar",
    "d": "Augustus"

    }
    ],
    "answer": "Romulus",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Which ancient city was the Capital of the Inca Empire?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Cuzco",
    "b": "Machu Picchu",
    "c": "Lima",
    "d": "Santiago"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Cuzco",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Who was the Founder of the Mauryan Empire?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Chandragupta Maurya",
    "b": "Ashoka the great",
    "c": "Bindusara",
    "d": "Brihadratha"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Chandragupta Maurya",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Which ancient Indian text is Considered the Oldest Scrpture of Hindusim?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Rigvedha",
    "b": "Yajurvedha",
    "c": "Samavedha",
    "d": "Atharvavda"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Rigvedha",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 7,
    "question": " Who founded the delhi sultanate in 1206 CE?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Qutab-ud-din Aibak",
    "b": " Alauddin Khalji",
    "c": "Muhammad Bin Tughlaq",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Qutab-ud-din Aibak",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Which Vijayanagar Emperor Built the Vittala Temple?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Harihara",
    "b": "Bukkaraya",
    "c": "Krishnadevaraya",
    "d": " Achyutharaya"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Krishnadevaraya",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Who was the Founder of the Mughal Empire?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Babur",
    "b": "Humayun",
    "c": "Akbar",
    "d": "Schah Jahan"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Babur",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Who let the Indian Rebellion of 1857 ?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Mangal Pandey",
    "b": "Ranilakshmi bhai",
    "c": "Tantia Tope",
    "d": "Bhahadur Shah",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Ranilakshmi bhai",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 11,
    "question": " Who was the First Viceroy of India?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Lord Canning",
    "b": "Lord Curzon",
    "c": "Lord Dalhoucie"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Lord canning",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Who lead the non-cooperation Movement in 1920-1922?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Mahathma Gandi",
    "b": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
    "c": "Subash Chandrabose",
    "d": "Lala Lajpat Rai"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Mahathma Gandi",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Who was India's First Prime Minister?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
    "b": "Subhas Chandrabose",
    "c": "Mahatma Gandi"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Who was the Architect of indians Constitution?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
    "b": "B R.Ambedkar",
    "c": "Mahatma Gandi"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "B R.Ambedkar",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "Who was the Founder of the Guptha Empire?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Siri Guptha",
    "b": "Ghatotkacha",
    "c": "Chandra Guptha-1",
    "d": "Samudra Guptha"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Chandra Guptha-1",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "Which ancient Indian Text Describies the Life of Buddha ?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Mahabaratha",
    "b": "Ramayana",
    "c": "Puranas",
    "d": "Pali Canon"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Pali Canon",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 17,
    "question": " Who was the Mughal Emperor who bulit the Tajmahal?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Akbar",
    "b": "Jahangir",
    "c": "Shah Jahan",
    "d": "Aurangzeb"
    }
    ],
    "answer":"Shah Jahan",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "Who was the First Indian to become a Member of the British Parliament?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Dadadhai Naoroji",
    "b": "Lala lajpat Rai"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Dadadhai Naoroji",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Who founded the Indian National Congress in 1885?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Lala lajpat Rai",
    "b": "Lallan Octavian hume"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Lallan Octavian hume",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 20,
    "question": " Who was the Indian's Second Prime Minister?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
    "b": "Gulzarilal Nanda",
    "c": "Lal Bahadur Shastri"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Lal Bahadur Shastri",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 21,
    "question": " Who was the first President of India",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Rajendra Prasad",
    "b": "Saravapelli Radhakrishanan",
    "c": "Zakir Husain",
    "d": "V.v.Giri"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Rajendra Prasad",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 22,
    "question": " Who was the Founder of the Pala Empire?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Gopala",
    "b": "Daramapala",
    "c": "Devapala"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Gopala",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "Who founded the Sultanate of Malwa in 1401 CE?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Hoshang Shah",
    "b": "Dilawaar khan",
    "c": "Mahumhat",
    "d": "Baz bahadur"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Dilawaar khan",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "Who was the founder of the Maratha Empire? ",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Shivaji",
    "b": "Sambhaji",
    "c": "Rajaram"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Shivaji",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "Who was the First Cheif Justice of India ?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "A.N. Roi",
    "b": "H.J.Kania"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "H.J.kania",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    }
    ]
    }
    var quizApp = function () {
    this.score = 0;
    this.qno = 1;
    this.currentque = 0;
    var totalque = quiz.JS.length;
    this.displayQuiz = function (cque) {
    this.currentque = cque;
    if (this.currentque < totalque) {
    $("#tque").html(totalque);
    $("#previous").attr("disabled", false);
    $("#next").attr("disabled", false);
    $("#qid").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].id + '.');
    $("#question").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].question);
    $("#question-options").html("");
    for (var key in quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0]) {
    if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0].hasOwnProperty(key)) {
    $("#question-options").append(
    "<div class='form-check option-block'>" +
    "<label class='form-check-label'>" +
    "<input type='radio' class='form-check-input' name='option' id='q" + key + "' value='" + quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] + "'><span id='optionval'>" +
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] +
    "</span></label>"
    );
    }
    }
    }
    if (this.currentque <= 0) {
    $("#previous").attr("disabled", true);
    }
    if (this.currentque >= totalque) {
    $('#next').attr('disabled', true);
    for (var i = 0; i < totalque; i++) {
    this.score = this.score + quiz.JS[i].score;
    }
    return this.showResult(this.score);
    }
    }
    this.showResult = function (scr) {
    $("#result").addClass('result');
    $("#result").html("<h1 class='res-header'>Total Score: &nbsp;" + scr + '/' + totalque + "</h1>");
    for (var j = 0; j < totalque; j++) {
    var res;
    if (quiz.JS[j].score == 0) {
    res = '<span class="wrong">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-remove c-wrong"></i>';
    } else {
    res = '<span class="correct">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-check c-correct"></i>';
    }
    $("#result").append(
    '<div class="result-question"><span>Q ' + quiz.JS[j].id + '</span> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].question + '</div>' +
    '<div><b>Correct answer:</b> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].answer + '</div>' +
    '<div class="last-row"><b>Score:</b> &nbsp;' + res +
    '</div>'
    );
    }
    }
    this.checkAnswer = function (option) {
    var answer = quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer;
    option = option.replace(/</g, "&lt;") //for <
    option = option.replace(/>/g, "&gt;") //for >
    option = option.replace(/"/g, "&quot;")
    if (option == quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer) {
    if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].score == "") {
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].score = 1;
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "correct";
    }
    } else {
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "wrong";
    }
    }
    this.changeQuestion = function (cque) {
    this.currentque = this.currentque + cque;
    this.displayQuiz(this.currentque);
    }
    }
    var jsq = new quizApp();
    var selectedopt;
    $(document).ready(function () {
    jsq.displayQuiz(0);
    $('#question-options').on('change', 'input[type=radio][name=option]', function (e) {
    //var radio = $(this).find('input:radio');
    $(this).prop("checked", true);
    selectedopt = $(this).val();
    });
    });
    $('#next').click(function (e) {
    e.preventDefault();
    if (selectedopt) {
    jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
    }
    jsq.changeQuestion(1);
    });
    $('#previous').click(function (e) {
    e.preventDefault();
    if (selectedopt) {
    jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
    }
    jsq.changeQuestion(-1);
    });